# **Amethyst White**

1020 University St. (Apt 507) Seattle, WA 98101 (360) 820-4986 || aybwhite@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/Am-White

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/amethyst-white-1942761b7/

I am a detail-oriented professional with exceptional interpersonal skills, team working abilities and 2 years of experience as a full stack developer. I specialize in Javascript, Next.js and React, with a deep interest in the front end design aspects and functionality of computer programming.

My art and design background allows me to offer additional skills and perspective to any coding or programming position.

## **WORK HISTORY:**

Vortex Games/Rushdown Revolt (Jr. Web Developer): February 2022- February 2023

- Hands on debugging with Git and Vercel
- Code optimization and SEO experience
- Attended out of state marketing conventions to support and boost the company

## HYTE/ Tabulara (Software Engineer): July 2021- December 2021

- Developing and optimizing front-end components
- Working remotely with a team of engineers, implementing designs, testing and debugging
- Provided qualitative and quantitative reports to the team

#### Valtesse Productions (Web Developer/Marketing and Advertising): June 2021- April 2022

- Managed MailChimp and Patreon notifications and posts
- Consulted on design aspects of the Maison de V and Valtesse webpages
- Created new pages using Javascript and HTML within Squarespace

### Freelance Web Development (Web Developer): June 2021- April 2022

- Built custom websites using Javascript, HTML, CSS and sites like squarespace
- Designing, implementing and maintaining front-end applications
- Handling all verbal and written communications between clients

## **LANGUAGES, TECH & SKILLS:**

**JavaScript JQuery Typescript** SEO's CSS JSON API's Vercel MvSOL HTML React Material Ui MongoDB **Responsive Designs** Accelbyte Ajax **NodeJS Typescript** Next.js **Figma** 

## **EDUCATION:**

One-on-One Coding Mentorship: With Kenan Stipek- Seattle, WA

May 2021 to 2022

Full Stack Coding Certificate: University of Washington and Trilogy - Seattle, WA

September 2020 to 2021

Graphic and Web Design Studies: Art Institute of Seattle - Seattle, WA

October 2018 to 2019

Associates in Arts and Science Degree: Whatcom Community College - Bellingham, WA

August 2014 to 2017

High School Diploma: Sehome High School - Bellingham, WA

September 2012 to 2016